<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--
    Usable with FlightGear
    Property of Gerard Robin

-->
<PropertyList>

  <title>Catalina PBY6  Water bomber</title>
  <key>
    <name>d</name>
    <desc>Blister open/close</desc>
  </key>
  <key>
    <name>D</name>
    <desc>water tank doors, close</desc>
  </key>
  <key>
    <name>s</name>
    <desc>Starter</desc>
  </key>
  <key>
    <name>f</name>
    <desc>Toggle Floats Up/Down</desc>
  </key>
  <key>
    <name>F</name>
    <desc>Toggle Mooring Anchor</desc>
  </key>
  <key>
    <name>l (like "l"etter) </name>
    <desc>release water over your target (water bombing)</desc>
  </key>
  <key>
    <name>L</name>
    <desc>Enable water scooping</desc>
  </key>
  <key>
    <name>B</name>
    <desc>toggle ON/OFF Brake Parking on ground or ON/OFF Cables/Anchor on water</desc>
  </key>
  <key>
    <name>m</name>
    <desc>Mixture auto rich</desc>
  </key>
  <key>
    <name>M</name>
    <desc>Mixture auto lean</desc>
  </key>
  <text><![CDATA[
This is a PBY-6 Catalina converted to a water-bomber, used in South-Eastern France from
1964 to 1970.  It is tuned (altitude, climb and speed) according to a payload of 10000
lbs, which is the water tank capacity filled up.

The fuel capacity is automatically limited for water-bombing when you press L.  You can
refuel only on ground, using the Catalina | Refuel dialog.

______________________ Procedures ______________________

Starting: use the Catalina | Easy Start menu.

Take off:
- release parking brakes (B)
- maximum throttle
- rotate at 70 knots

Stopping engines:
- magneto switches OFF.

Scooping water into the tanks:
- Floats down (f)
- Open the filling dialog (Catalina | Reload Water)
- Press L to initiate scooping
- Skim the water at 100 knots with half throttle, pushing the elevator gently
- Increase throttle slowly as your plane gets heavier.
- When the load is complete (4530 l), full throttle and lift off.
- Use ground effect as long as possible to gain speed before climbing.
- Floats up (f).

Igniting a fire:
- In the menu Environment | Wildfire Settings, tick Enabled.
- Shift+Ctrl+left click on the ground to ignite a fire.
- Warning: too many fires will slow your computer down, even after you
  extinguish them.

Dropping water:
- fly at 200 ft above ground.
- press l (lowercase L) or in the Reload Water menu, press the Launch button.
- your aircraft will become 4500 kg lighter and soar up; prepare for it.
- close water bomb doors (D).

______________________ Mooring ______________________

It is a Seaplane, so i have included the mooring feature which is part of the
wonderful model seaplane Boeing314
 
To start from an airport which has a close mooring place, situate the seaplane
automatically on that place, with Floats DOWN.
 
For example KSFO which has a mooring place on the San Fransisco Bay near Bay
Bridge or LFML (Marseilles Marignane) has a mooring place on the Etang de Berre.
 
The cables which hold the aircraft in place, are simulated, with the
"Brake Parking" feature

______________________ Eye Candy ______________________
If you want to get the best of this model, we recommend Rembrandt rendering
giving real shadows and lights.  It should not slow your computer. For instance
with a GPU Nvidia  GT 560 TI we get 40 frames per second at LFML.
]]>
  </text>
</PropertyList>
